# PAULO RIBEIRO

# FULL STACK DEVELOPER

### CONTACT

paulofr17@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/paulo-ribeiro17/



github.com/paulofr17/



paulo-ribeiro.vercel.app



Porto, Portugal

### HARD SKILLS

- React
- Next
- Angular
- Tailwind
- Prisma
- Node
- Relational Databases (SQL)
- NoSQL Databases (MongoDB)
- Salesforce Development

### SOFT SKILLS

- Problem-Solving
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Resilience
- Adaptability

## EDUCATION

## Master's degree in Computer Science

Universidade do Minho

2019 - 2021

#### **Bachelor's in Computer Science**

Universidade do Minho

2015 - 2019

### PROFILE

I'm a Full Stack Developer who's been working in the Salesforce ecosystem since 2021. Currently in a Senior Analyst role, I'm responsible for designing, customizing and configuring Salesforce solutions to meet our client needs. However, my journey in software development extends beyond the Salesforce ecosystem.

I've gained proficiency in both front-end and back-end development through handson experience with the personal projects listed below.

I'm now seeking new challenges in a full stack developer role where I can further leverage my skill set and passion for technology.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Salesforce Developer - Senior Analyst

Accenture

2021 - Current

- · Designing and developing custom user interfaces using Visualforce Pages, Aura Components and Lightning Web Components
- · Writing unit tests and performing code reviews to ensure the quality and stability of the solutions developed
- Implementing complex business logic, triggers, batch processes, and integrations with external systems using Apex
- · Setting up user profiles, roles, permission sets, field-level security, and sharing rules to control access to data and functionality
- Collaborating with stakeholders to gather and analyze business requirements, translating them into technical specifications for Salesforce solutions

## **Data Scientist - Internship**

Celfocus

2020 - 2021

• Collaborated with the Quality Assurance (QA) team to integrate AI models into existing toolsets, developing a plugin to automate the process of identification and classification of vulnerabilities in authentication cookies

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

### Task Manager

- Task Manager is an app developed with Next.js + Prisma + MongoDB designed to help users organize and prioritize their tasks efficiently using Kanban Boards
- It enables users to create Workspaces, Projects, and collaborate seamlessly
- Includes dashboards for task tracking and enhancing productivity

#### **Sneakers Store**

- Sneakers Store is an ecommerce website with a user-friendly interface. It includes essential features such as product catalog with filtering, user authentication, user orders history, shopping cart, and backoffice pages
- Developed using React + Next + Tailwind in the front-end and Node + Express + Supabase in the back-end
- Prior to transitioning to React + Next, I initially developed a simpler version using Angular for the front-end